<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
  <file>
    <title>Conditions tab</title>
    
    <breadcumbs>
      <text>
        <link file="Environment.html">Development environment</link>
        ->
        <link file="Environment/IfPart.html">Conditions tab</link>
      </text>
    </breadcumbs>
    
    <descriptionarticle >
      <p>
        <text>
          <b>Conditions</b> make it possible to specify whether the action should be executed at the moment or not.
         Condition is a kind of rule, it is usually a <b>comparison</b> (e.g. 
          <link file="Objects/Window/PropertiesCommands/Text.html">the text of the window</link> is equal to "Window1"
          or <link file="Objects/Button/PropertiesCommands/Width.html">the button width</link> is more than 100) and all
          <link file="Environment/ActionPart.html">actions</link> 
          created in the framework of this condition are executed
          only when the <b>condition is true</b> (i.e.
          <link file="Objects/Window/PropertiesCommands/Text.html">the text of the window</link> is actually equal to "Window1"
          and <link file="Objects/Button/PropertiesCommands/Width.html">the button width</link> is more than 100)
        </text>
      </p>
      <textAll>
        <p>
          You can <b>set the condition</b> in the Conditions tab of
          <link file="Environment.html">Algorithm2 development environment</link>:
          <imgMy src="IfPart.jpg"></imgMy>
        </p>
        <p>
          There you should specify the <b>condition itself</b> in the form of: "something" is equal/unequally to "something" 
          ("unequally" is specified by the symbol &lt;&gt;, "more or equal" - by the symbol &gt;=)
          <codesnip><![CDATA[Window1.Text1.Text = "Required text"
Window1.Window1.Width > "200"
Window1.Button1.Fore color <> black
Window1.Window1.X >= Window1.Text1.Text]]></codesnip>
          After you have clicked the button <b>Create</b> a condition block will appear in the 
          <link file="Environment/TreePart.html">Actions tree</link>:
        </p>
        <p> <imgMy src="IfPart2.jpg"></imgMy>      </p>
        <p>
          Now all <link file="Environment/ActionPart.html">actions</link> inside of this condition block 
          (in the example there is just one action - to make the window hidden) would be executed
          <b>only in case</b> the Text of the object Window1 is equal to "Window"
        </p>
        <p>
          But there is more to come. You can also create <b>otherCases</b> and a section <b>In all other cases</b>.
          To do this <b>click</b> on the created <b>standard condition</b> and use the conditions tab.
        </p>
        <p>
          <imgMy src="IfPart3.jpg"></imgMy>
          <codesnip2>
            <textAll>
              <p>
                Note: Symbol <b>_AND</b> is used to show that <b>both conditions</b> of the string:
                and "Window1.Window1.Width &gt; 100" and "Window1.Window1.Width &lt; 300" should be met.
                Along with <b>_AND</b> there is a symbol <b>_OR</b> which means that the condition is true
                <b>even if one of the conditions</b> is true, i.e. either "Window1.Window1.Width &gt; 100",
                or "Window1.Window1.Width &lt; 300".
                All this you can do using <link file="Environment/Master.html">Complex operations wizard</link> (click on the button with a magic wand on it)
              </p>
            </textAll>
          </codesnip2>
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>otherCases:</b><br/>
          They are verified only in case a standard condition is <b>false</b>.
          If the otherCase is true, then <b>its</b> actions are executed. If false, then the
          <b>next</b> otherCases are verified. OtherCases are created in the same way as standard conditions.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>In all other cases:</b><br/>
          This section is aimed for cases when the condition and otherCases (if they are given) are <b>false</b>.
          All its actions would be executed only if condition is not true.
        </p>
      </textAll>
    </descriptionarticle>
    
    <remarks>
      <text>Conditions can be not only <b>simple</b> (texts or numbers comparison), but also <b>complex</b>
      (formula, comparing with a property value of the other object).
      To create a complex condition use
      <link file="Environment/Master.html">Complex operations wizard</link> (click on the button with a magic wand on it).
        <p>
          You can interrupt a condition pre-term, without waiting for the rest of actions have been executed. Learn more about it in the section
          <link file="UsefulObjects.html">Useful Objects</link>.<link file="UsefulObjects/_Interrupts.html">Interrupts</link>
        </p>
      </text>
    </remarks>

    <seealso>
      <est/>
      <link file="Environment.html">Development environment</link><br/>
      <link file="Objects.html">Objects</link><br/>
      <link file="UsefulObjects/_Interrupts.html">Interrupts</link>
    </seealso>
  </file>
</xml>