<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
  <file>
    <title>Settings</title>
    
    <breadcumbs>
      <text>
        <link file="Environment.html">Development environment</link>
        ->
        <link file="Environment/Options.html">Settings</link>
      </text>
    </breadcumbs>
    
    <descriptionarticle >
      <p>
        <text>
          You can open a configuration dialog box by selecting menu items <b>Tools</b> -> <b>Settings</b>. Dialog box sections:
        </text>
      </p>
      <textAll>
        <p>
          <b>Interface language:</b><br/>
          Here you can choose a language of <b>development environment</b>. All menus and titles will be shown in the language specified, but the language in which the project has been created initially remains for all actions and programming.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Programming language:</b><br/>
          is the language in which all <b>new</b> projects will be programmed after the given option has been changed, but the language in which the <b>current</b> project has been created initially remains for all actions and programming of this project. To change the language of the current project select
          menu items <b>Tools</b> -> <b>Translate project into</b>.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Skin:</b><br/>
          is a theme of Algorithm2 development environment.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Project Folder:</b><br/>
          is a folder where all projects are stored on default. You can create your own directories there.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Default folder with project images:</b><br/>
          When you specify images in the <link file="Environment/PropertiesPart.html">Properties panel</link>
         they are automatically copied into a <b>special image folder</b> which is stored in the 
          <b> directory of your project</b>. You can <b>rename</b> this image folder in this setting
          and it will have this title in all <b>new</b> projects, but for the current project it <b>won't change</b>.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Current project's images folder:</b><br/>
          When you specify images in the <link file="Environment/PropertiesPart.html">Properties panel</link>
         they are automatically copied into a special image folder which is stored in the 
          directory of your project. You can <b>rename</b> this image folder in this setting
          and the title <b>will be changed</b> right for the current project.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Default image filename:</b><br/>
          When you specify images in the <link file="Environment/PropertiesPart.html">Properties panel</link>
          they are automatically copied into a special image folder which is stored in
          the directory of your project. The <b>image title</b> changes to the title specified in this setting.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Program's icon:</b><br/>
          When you create an <b>exe</b>-file of your project (File -> Compile Executable) the file gets an icon specified in this option.
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Show loading window at the project start:</b><br/>
          When users <b>run</b> your program it takes <b>some time</b> for the program to be loaded completely and to be displayed. So during this time a 
          <b>loading window</b> with a progress bar is being displayed to the user. In this setting you can disable the option.
        </p>
      </textAll>
    </descriptionarticle>

    <seealso>
      <est/>
      <link file="Environment.html">Development environment</link>
    </seealso>
  </file>
</xml>