<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
  <file>
    <title>Object events</title>
    <breadcumbs>
      <link file="UsefulObjects.html">Useful Objects</link>
      <text>
        -> <objLink/>
      </text>
    </breadcumbs>
    
    <descriptionarticle only="false">
      <p>
        <text>The useful object <b>Object events</b> makes accessible the properties and commands of <b>that</b> object
        where the <link file="Environment/EventPart.html">event</link> is being executed at the moment.</text>
      </p>
       <p>
        <textAll>Example:
          <imgMy src="EventObj.jpg"></imgMy>

          There <b>Object events</b> makes accessible the properties and commands of the <b>Button1</b>, because it is in the event <b>Click</b> of this button.
          <p>
            Thus the useful object <b>Object events</b> has <b>nothing new</b>, it just <b>simplifies</b> the process of actions
            creation. Now in case it is necessary to <b>change the property</b> of the object where the <b>event</b> has been executed, there is no need to specify its <b>name</b> (e.g. Button1), but simply a universal name "Object events" can be specified. This is very helpful, for example, when <link file="Programming/Array.html">arrays</link> are used.
          </p>
          <p>
             <b>All properties</b> which are possible under different <b>events</b> and different
          <b>objects</b> are included in <b>Object events</b> in advance. That's why <b>not all</b> properties and commands are available under every particular event, but only properties and commands of the <b>object</b> where the given event has been executed. In the example only those properties and commands of <b>Object events</b> work, which are included in the  object Button1 (Text in the given example).
          </p> </textAll>
      </p>
      <p>
        <i>
          <text>Features of the object:</text>
        </i>
        <childlist>
          <child icon="27" fileMy="PropertiesCommands.html">
            <name>Properties and Commands</name>
            <descr>
              <descrProperties/>
            </descr>
          </child>
        </childlist>
      </p>
    </descriptionarticle>
    
    <seealso>
      <est/>
      Other <link file="UsefulObjects.html">Useful Objects
    </link>
    </seealso>
    
  </file>
</xml>
